JESSICA CLAIRE

resumesample@example

(555) 432-1000.

, , 100 Montgomery St. 1 Floor

-

8

• :

A

:: P

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Data Scientist with over 4 years of successful experience in Machine Learning, NLP, and Predictive Modeling. Recognized consistently for performance excellence and $% \left(1\right) =\left(1\right) \left(1\right) \left$ contributions to success in business industry. Strengths in math and programming skill backed by training in data science.

SKILLS

- Database: MySQL, Postgres MongoDB,
- Programming Language: Py and R
- Machine Learning
- · Data Mining
- Natural Language Processin
- Statistical analysis
- A/B Testing
- Project Management
- Agile framework understan
- Big-Data: HBase, Hadoop, Hive, and Spark
- Operating Systems: LINUX, WINDOW.
- Environment: AWS, AZURE, Databricks.

EDUCATION

Colorado State University Fort Collins, CO • 05/2019 â€

Master of Science: Applied Statistics Specialization Data Science - GPA: GPA: 3.43 /4.00

Professional development completed in Data Science

Addis Ababa University Addis Ababa, • 06/2011 – –

Master of Science: Biochemistry & Biophysics - GPA: GPA: 3.50 /4.00

Addis Ababa University Addis, Ababa 08/2003 – –

Bachelor of Science: Medical Laboratory Technology - GPA:

CERTIFICATIONS

Introduction of TensorFlow Al, Machine Learning and De Learning Training - Nov 201

WORK HISTORY

Yahoo! - Data Scientist

New York, NY, · · 06/2019 - Current

- Transformed raw data into MySQL with custom-made ETL application to prepare unruly data for machine learning
- Performed data cleaning, features scaling, featurization, features engineering used Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn in Python at various stages for developing machine learning model and A/B Testing, multi-variate to measure impact on new initiatives.
- Used spark's machine learning library to build and evaluate different models.
- Developed end-to-end machine learning prototypes and scaled them to run in Aws sagemaker notebooks.
- Collaborated with internal stakeholders, identifying and gathering analytical requirements for customer, product and projects needs
- Provided comprehensive analysis and recommend solutions to address complex business problems and issues using data from internal and external sources and applied advanced analytical methods to assess factors impacting growth and profitability across product and service offerings

Epic Games - Capstone Project

Colorado Springs, CO, • • 09/2017 - 06/2019

- Built Recommendation system using cosine similarity to choose similar songs added to given playlist.
- Customer Churn Prediction Projects . Pick up top model based on recall score. Evaluated models using Cross validation, recall used to measure performance and used ROC curves and AUC for feature selection.
- Predict product categories for ibotta datasets. Built machine learning classifier for many datasets and applied data mining to improve text quality by autocorrecting grammatical issues.
- Analysis on NBA Real Plus-Minus for 2014-2015 Regular Seasons. Applied multiple regression to examine relationship between players' performances and numerical variables.
- Potato Virus Y detection using machine learning algorithms. Pick up top model for detection of potato Y virus in potato $\hat{a} \in \mathbb{T}$ s seed from Xgboost, Random Forest, SVM, Decision Tree, kNN and Logitboost on chemical fingerprinting datasets.

Houston Methodist - Research Scientist

Jacksonville, FL, • • 11/2015 - 05/2019

- Use data visualization tools to help tell story about findings from data to people who are not necessarily data-literate.
- Performed data collection, data cleaning and analysis and re-coding of existing vendor laboratory computer software.
- Ability to collaborate effectively with mentor and others in lab on new research projects.
- Excellent interpersonal skills, cross-group, and cross-culture collaboration.
- Lead Quality Assurance Data Management in different instruments, evaluation, and analysis of QA/QC data, identifying trends and shift and taking corrective $% \left(1\right) =\left(1\right) \left(1\right) \left($

Swedish Medical Center - Medical Laboratory Scientist City, STATE, • • 11/2011 - 10/2015

- Collect, store, retrieve, analyze and present data.
- Issues and regularly interfaces with hospital staff and administrators regarding their finding and collaborate with teams to integrate systems.
- Help clinicians and other staff troubleshoot technology issues and regularly interface with hospital staff and administrators regarding their findings and collaborate with teams to integrate systems.
- Led quality control diagnostic testing, documenting all variances in results and blood product performance.